The mystery. The life. The love. The legend.
Dragon: The Bruce Lee Story is a drama, history,
action film directed by Rob Cohen.
This film is a glimpse into the life, love and the
unconquerable spirit of the legendary Bruce Lee.
From a childhood of rigorous martial arts training, Lee realizes his
dream of opening his own kung-fu school in America.
Before long, he is discovered by a Hollywood producer and begins a meteoric rise to fame and an
all too short reign as one the most charismatic action heroes in cinema history.
Bruce Lee, played by Jason Scott Lee.
Linda Lee, played by Lauren Holly.
Bill Krieger, played by Robert Wagner.
Vivian Emery, played by Michael Learned.
Gussie Yang, played by Nancy Kwan.
Philip Tan, played by Lim Kay Tong.
Dragon: The Bruce Lee Story is a 1993 American
biographical drama film directed by Rob Cohen.
The film stars Jason Scott Lee, with a supporting cast
including Lauren Holly, Nancy Kwan, and Robert Wagner.
The film follows the life of actor and martial artist Bruce Lee (Jason) from his relocation to the United States
from Hong Kong to his career as a martial arts teacher, and then as a television and film actor.
It also focuses on the relationship between Bruce and his wife
Linda, and the racism to which Bruce was subjected.
The primary source of the screenplay is Cadwell's 1975
biography Bruce Lee: The Man Only I Knew.
Other sources include Robert Clouse's book Bruce Lee: The Biography and research by
Cohen, including interviews with Cadwell and Bruce's son, Brandon Lee.
Rather than a traditional biographical film, Cohen decided to include elements of mysticism and to
dramatise fight scenes to give it the same tone as the films in which Bruce starred.
Dragon was filmed primarily in Hong Kong, Los Angeles and San Francisco.
Dragon: The Bruce Lee Story received generally positive reviews, with critics
finding it entertaining despite criticisms of its veneration of Bruce.
Jason was widely praised for his performance.
The film was a commercial success and its revenue exceeded box office averages for biographical films, which was
attributed to its romantic themes and its appeal to people outside the traditional kung fu film audience.
A video game adaptation of the same name was released the following year.
Dragon is dedicated to Brandon, who died several weeks before its release.
The film explores themes of martial arts, kung fu,
life and death, training, biography.
The tone is emotional.